<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="110245" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="UrbanInequality" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="This mod adds realistic building progression based on education, income, and global level caps. Create diverse, unequal cities where only the most developed areas reach the top." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
## Urban Inequality – Realistic Building Growth

Urban Inequality transforms the way buildings evolve in your city by introducing realistic socio-economic dynamics. Inspired by real-world urban development patterns, this mod creates a city where not every neighborhood becomes a utopia — and where growth is earned.

## Features
* Education-Based Progression: Building upgrades now consider the education level of adult and senior residents. Higher education leads to faster growth, while low education holds neighborhoods back.
* Income-Driven Penalties: Low-income households face harsher conditions for leveling up, mimicking real-world development disparities.
* City-Wide Level Caps: Set realistic caps on how many buildings can reach each level — for example, only 5–10% of all buildings might become level 5, just like in actual cities.
* Realistic Wage Profiles: Each resident level earns a configurable monthly wage. Choose from real-world city presets where lower levels earn modest incomes and higher levels reflect upper-class wealth — within the game’s scale.
* 22 Real City Presets: Apply building-level distributions and wage structures modeled after cities like Tokyo, São Paulo, Chicago, Santiago, London, and more — each with realistic inequality baked in.
* Fully Configurable: Adjust penalty strength and level cap percentages directly from the settings menu.

Bulding level upgrade limitations only applies to residential buildings. Also, wage profiles are not set by default, so you can choose the one that fits your city best in the settings menu.

## Note on Existing Cities
This mod does not retroactively downgrade or restrict already-upgraded buildings. The new rules apply only to future upgrades that happen after the mod is enabled. For the most immersive experience, it’s best used from the start of a new city.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/urban-inequality-mod.1760203/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.3" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.3.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Required DLC, can be set multiple times. Supported values are "Landmark Buildings", "San Fransisco Set", "Beach Properties", "Urban Promenades", "Modern Architecture"-->
	<RequiredDLC Value="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
		* Updated for game version 1.3
		* Added Chicago and Santiago presets
		* Added option to configure wages 
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link, can be set multiple times. supported types are "discord", "github", "youtube", "twitch", "x", "paypal", "patreon", "buymeacoffee", "kofi", "crowdin", "gitlab", "gofundme"-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/UrbanInequality" />
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.com/channels/1024242828114673724/1376574485603287041" />
	<ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/ruzbeh0" />
	<ExternalLink Type="kofi" Url="https://ko-fi.com/ruzbeh0" />
</Publish>
